<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<community_archives xmlns="http://emmd.com/em/terms/"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://emmd.com/em/terms/ file:/Users/erinmustard/LIS524/Draft4_reorganized.xsd">
    <identifier xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">CA-NYGBS</identifier>
    <repository>
        <corpname>New York Genealogical and Biographical Society</corpname>
        <address>36 West 44th Street 7th Floor
            New York, NY 10036-8105</address>
    </repository>
    <contactInformation>
        <website>https://www.newyorkfamilyhistory.org/volunteer</website>
        <website>https://www.newyorkfamilyhistory.org/form/webform-168326</website>
        <emailAddress>Use contact form</emailAddress>
        <phoneNumber>212-755-8532</phoneNumber>
        <contact_name>NA</contact_name>
    </contactInformation>
    <volunteerActivities>
        <volunteerTask>Digitization</volunteerTask>
        <volunteerTask>Indexing</volunteerTask>
        <volunteerTask>Record Retrieval</volunteerTask>
    </volunteerActivities>
    <positionDescription>
        <head>Digitization of New York Records</head>
        <experienceRequired>There is also opportunity for volunteers with 
            significant digitization experience to become Digital Project 
            Assistants overseeing the work of volunteers in the Digitization 
            Center.</experienceRequired>
        <applicationRequired>Interest form</applicationRequired>
        <part>Begun in 2017, the New York Digitization and Indexing Project aims 
            to place thousands of new materials online. To date we have indexed 
            more than 50,000 records and digitized more than 86,000.As part of 
            our mission to preserve New York history, we actively work on digitizing 
            records and documents. Volunteers doing digitization will be trained 
            on the use of our scanning equipment, image quality control, 
            and best practices for file management.Our Digitization Center has four 
            digitization stations that we aim to have working on a continuous basis 
            Monday through Friday 9:00 AM–5:00 PM with volunteers working in three or 
            four-hour shifts when possible.</part>
    </positionDescription>
    <positionDescription>
        <head>Indexing of New York Records</head>
        <experienceRequired>Unknown</experienceRequired>
        <applicationRequired>Interest form</applicationRequired>
        <part>Our indexing team adds new records that can be searched online. 
            Indexing can be done in the office or from the convenience of your 
            own home anywhere in the world. Volunteers are given scanned document 
            pages in batches and are asked to complete an indexing form for each batch.</part>
    </positionDescription>
    <positionDescription>
        <head>Record Retrieval</head>
        <experienceRequired>Experience in using local repositories across New York State</experienceRequired>
        <applicationRequired>Interest form</applicationRequired>
        <part>Record retrieval involves traveling to a repository and getting a copy 
            or a digital picture of a specific record that a member has identified 
            such as a family file from the Milstein Division of the New York Public 
            Library or a birth certificate at the NYC Municipal Archives.</part>
    </positionDescription>
    <instructionalMethod xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">Training on use of scanning equipment
    image quality control, and best practices for file management</instructionalMethod>
    <internetAccess>Yes</internetAccess>
    <description xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">A core part of the New York Genealogical and 
        Biographical Society's mission is to preserve historical material and make it accessible 
        for New York State genealogy and history research.Our society has always used contemporary 
        technology to make this material accessible to a wide audience—in our early decades, we 
        disseminated transcriptions of crucial records and other genealogical research in a periodical,  
        The New York Genealogical and Biographical Record, which is still in publication today. 
        In the twentieth century, NYG&amp;B scholars and archivists traveled all over New York State 
        transcribing records, which were bound into books and disseminated to universities, 
        libraries, and individual researchers. In the twenty-first century, our society digitizes 
        images of historical records and creates searchable databases to allow researchers to 
        search and view these documents online. </description>
    <context>As a 501(c)(3) nonprofit organization, our mission is to preserve, document, 
        and share family history and stories from across New York State. We engage with 
        genealogists, biographers, historians, and organizations to establish the broader 
        contexts of New York’s past. We actively foster connections between New York’s past 
        and present. For the past 150 years, we have been preserving valuable genealogical 
        and historical records, producing peer-reviewed genealogical scholarship, and providing 
        crucial resources to help amateur and professional genealogists navigate New York 
        genealogy research.</context>
    <controlaccess>
        <head>Library of Congress Subject Headings</head>
        <subject xmlns="http://ead3.archivists.org/schema/" encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">
            <part>Genealogy &amp; local history</part>
        </subject>
        <subject xmlns="http://ead3.archivists.org/schema/" encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">
            <part>Biographies</part>
        </subject>
    </controlaccess>
    <arrangement>
        <head>Category</head>
        <list xmlns="http://ead3.archivists.org/schema/">
            <item>Account Books</item>
            <item>Biographies</item>
            <item>Business</item>
            <item>Cemetery</item>
            <item>Census</item>
            <item>Colonial</item>
            <item>Compiled Genealogies</item>
            <item>County Histories</item>
            <item>Court</item>
            <item>Death</item>
            <item>Directories</item>
            <item>Personal and Family Papers</item>
            <item>Immigration</item>
            <item>Index</item>
            <item>Marriage Contracts</item>
            <item>Naturalization</item>
            <item>Newspapers</item>
            <item>Occupations</item>
            <item>Periodicals</item>
            <item>Religious Records</item>
            <item>Research Aids</item>
            <item>Town Records</item>
            <item>Unlocked</item>
            <item>Vital Records</item>
            <item>Wills and Probate</item>    
        </list>
        <p xmlns="http://ead3.archivists.org/schema/">Can also be organized by location, type
        of material, and creator of the records</p>
    </arrangement>
    <relation xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">The New York Public Library, Stephen
    A. Schwarzman Building (Fifth Avenue and 42nd Street) located both in the Manuscript
    Division and the Irma and Paul Milstein Division of United States History,
    Local History and Geneaology. </relation>
    <audience xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">genealogists</audience>
    <architecturalContext>
        <part>The NYG &amp; B also moved to its present home at 36 West 44th Street.</part>
        <architecturalContextDate>early 2000s</architecturalContextDate>
    </architecturalContext>
    <preservationLevel>Records from New York State are digitized, and offer
    digitization services to organizations and individuals that possess records related to New York State.</preservationLevel>
</community_archives>